i leave for a week and i come back to
some of the biggest amount of progress
that i've seen in a while there's an
airfield here look at this
the amount of detail in this with the
left and the right and that
there's not even any aircraft this is
scar you've you've gone mad you've gone
absolutely mental there's a tower there
the the hangar is now over the side i
can even see inside of that i can't
really tell what it is from here but
look at this they are definitely up to
something and
do you see that that portal looks
absolutely demolished
how have they done this i really
shouldn't go inside but what if i sort
of just float around here
no it's not a glitch it's that's real
that's a real that's a real cursed
portal right there
how weird
and it looks like there's been a little
accident over here with a gigantic
explosion
i don't know what these guys are up to
but i don't like it and as you know
ren and i have set up shop over here in
our little hippie vans let's pop some
music on because we've got some work to
do well i've actually already been doing
some work down here as you can see i
have been digging a big hole big holes
are very useful in minecraft because you
can hide things from the man and
basically what fred and i are going to
do if we've sort of hashed out an entire
plan
we're going to dig a tunnel over to area
semi-central
just inside area 77 but we have to make
sure that we're not seen at any point
and i'm kind of counting on you guys not
to let them know
because
yeah this is this is pretty important
that this stays secret but to stop them
kind of coming in and just exploring all
this for themselves because i haven't
really hidden that very well i mean you
can see it from the outside
i'm gonna make sure that we hide this
properly from them we need a barrier of
some kind and i sort of started over
here with this very pathetic ball but i
need to do some terraining
to create some sort of cliff to just
stop them coming in and
being able to see exactly what we're
doing at all times which is basically
what they can do now
so seeing as i've been away for a week
that i do have an awful lot that i need
to do but let's start this little time
lapse of some very basic terraining to
get a cliff going
so that we can hide what we're doing a
little better and then we can crack on
with the
lava game that i have over there and i
actually want to try out scar's new mini
oh there it is i want to try out this
game here because you can make some
diamonds there but let's get this out of
the way first
so what i'm doing here is i'm going to
create some scar-like terraining around
our little hippie commune so we can get
some privacy so a little bit of a cliff
and i'm paying the most attention to the
two sides that are the most exposed and
i'm paying particular attention to the
side that faces area 77 because we don't
want them to be able to see what we're
up to or at least we want them to try
and be intrigued by what we're doing but
terraining it takes a long time and it's
a very very tedious job but you can do a
lot with a little that little cliff has
a lot of details in it i just gotta say
thousands of thousands of stone and dirt
went into this and then i placed all the
kind of vegetation so that the trees
grow around it and to create some sort
of foliage barrier i think this looks
pretty cool
i think that is a pretty formidable wall
you cannot see inside the hippie commune
at all obviously they can walk in but
i can walk in here as well so they've
got this truck here which looks pretty
cool by the way i don't know who made
this probably scar but it actually looks
really cool and they've got a couple of
armor stands here
watching us
with
a bat head and um
observer so what i thought we could do
is two people can play at this game they
might be watching us they can't see
anything now
but we can also do something for them as
well
i just need to find the right spot which
isn't here oh this is a dangerous place
no this is a dangerous place oh this is
a very dangerous place please don't
please i just terrained all this why
don't i light anything up no
no
why are there so many ah
well that's a bit annoying okay that's a
little better actually you know what
this might be a lot easier if we work
from the outside in and also while we're
here
we can plant some peace flags just so
they know they're dealing with someone
that just wants to be friends there we
go so if they are looking
about
that looks like a really good spot right
here
so what i'm gonna do is just a
little spot with a glass window in just
like they have then we're gonna add an
armor stand right there and we're gonna
add a vindicator head to it so he kind
of blends in with all of the stone and
then from the outside this should look
pretty funny
so let's go and have a look at our new
spy so they're looking at us he's even
it even looks like he's pointing over
there oh i need to give him like some
leather armor or whatever but that
that's pretty cool and you know what i
think every episode we could add a
couple more so if they notice them
they'll notice that like two more are
coming up three more actually i've got a
really good idea that we can do over the
next few episodes that includes adding
more and more of these
there we go so i've got a leather tunic
if i make that
light gray
there we go that gives him some clothes
and it makes him look less like an armor
stand
there we go two can play at this game
they've got spies
we've got spies
but as i said before i actually wanted
this area the hippie commune to be
kind of useful
and i thought what we could do if it's
even possible is to create microfarms
inside of these rvs so i'm going to give
it a go obviously there's not a lot of
room for redstone and the limited
redstone that i can do
it definitely doesn't really
compact very well so this is going to be
a learning curve but i'm pretty sure
with a little bit of research maybe with
a little bit of help as well
we can make something
that will fit inside here the great
thing is that i've already made one rv
so it's kind of just a case of copying
it but i need to make sure that they
look slightly different not everyone has
the same rv that would be super
embarrassing if you turned up to a
hippie commune and everyone has the same
rv
so to start off with something really
really simple i thought what we could do
is make a little dive farm now obviously
these are so simple it's unbelievable
but i think it's one of those things
that fits really well into our whole
hippie theme and it fits rather nicely
into this rv
so
all i've got to do is get some
dispensers and then make a clock and
then it should span these out pretty
swiftly i've got the dispenser set up
i've built somewhat of the rv it's kind
of similar to mine but a little bit
different either way
what we're going to do is hop into the
van and build the redstone for this now
hmm
i'm kind of guessing but i
i think i've actually learned a bit of
redstone just through osmosis okay so i
don't really know what i'm doing but i
just i think this will work just give me
a second if i place the sticky piston
there place an observer like that and
all i've got to do is just get these
activating over and over again
so
bit of redstone dust over the top all
the way here
and it literally should be as simple as
that actually i need to just fill them
up full of
some bone meal if i am correct which i'm
probably not
i place the lever here i switch it on
well what do you know
i mean that's the most basic redstone in
the world but
it's producing flowers
sweet
and it produces them quickly as well
then i can just take those turn those
into dyes and we've got a pretty
successful dye farm right here now
obviously these are only some basic
colors we got some red we got some
magenta this is probably pink over here
so we're gonna have to make another farm
another day for all the other colors
but this is a really good start now all
i need to do is collect them using a
hopper system
how does one do that
well the first thing that we can do
before we worry about that is finish off
this rv just needs a roof now and maybe
some finer detailing but then that's
pretty much complete there we go that's
the basic rv pretty much complete
this hippie commune is coming together
rather nicely
i'm just gonna do a little test on again
this is redstone that i've learned kind
of just by watching other people i don't
actually know what i'm doing but if this
works this will be a pretty big step in
me understanding redstone a little more
so i'm just gonna add this one here to
see if this works all right we lose some
but
it's all going in
now does it end up in
well there we go problem solved so in
theory all i've got to do is replicate
this over this might not be ideal for
the long term but at least the short
term i think this will work quite well
so if i add this for full
efficiency
and i turn this on
that that seems to be working we've got
ourselves an rv flower farm
it's beautiful now obviously this only
gives us pink magenta and red dye i
could add a sunflower one here as well
because there's actually a couple more
of these uh two tall flowers that we can
use but i do actually as i said earlier
want to create a small flower farm but
that will cover pretty much yellow uh so
don't have to worry too much let's take
a look at how quickly this gets through
the bone meal because that's kind of a
big factor
oh boy
i guess i only have to wait for this to
run out and then i've got to restock it
so it's not perfect
fortunately i have all of these bone
blocks to get through so we have pretty
much unlimited flowers now if i want to
access it that's a bit of a different
story because
the chests at the moment
are all up there it sounds like it's run
out of bone meal already
but let's see what we've got
lots
and lots of flowers
and i've just had a thought
this is me starting to think a bit more
like a redstone person but i can add a
chest and a hopper to refill these
dispensers as it it rocks through all of
the bone meal to keep it topped up
unfortunately i do have to spend a
little bit of time decrafting everything
and filling up all of these chests which
is it's pretty tedious but
it's fairly easy to do
so i've got all of these chests now full
of bone meals so they can then feed into
the dispensers and it won't run out
nearly as quickly and we'll have all of
those dyes
this is
actually really cool i couldn't i can
totally see why making farms is fun for
a lot of people it's just like the only
thing i'll say is that
this is an easy farm
maybe i'll learn redstone properly next
season now with that rv done that's kind
of one of the farms the big flower farm
i know i forgot the sunflower but i'll
add it in another time when i actually
find one i haven't actually seen a
sunflower so when i see one i'll add it
to the new
rv flower machine but there is actually
something i want to do
while this machine was running i mean
it's run out of bone meal already but
look how much look how much flours i've
got
like each one of these is going to make
two die i basically have unlimited
magenta dye here so so much guy but what
i want to do is because ren is actually
on right now i don't know where he is
but he's going to be building some stuff
in the hippie commune too so i want to
make sure i plan something out before he
builds here because this area isn't
going to be just this corner we're going
to make this
really big
so what i'm going to be making is a
little bit of a secret i'm not going to
lie
but it's important for the future of the
hippie commune and it might not make
immediate sense what this is going to be
but in the future this
circle that i'm making will play quite a
big part in what we're going to be doing
basically
we've got while we're working our way
towards area 77 to come up with
different ways of distracting doc and
scar from what we're doing we've
obviously hidden ourselves using this
really
nice looking natural minecraft tree
barrier but we've also got to distract
them in other ways and this is where the
giant circle comes in
there we go we've got the full circle
right here this is actually quite large
in size and it's going to take up a good
portion of the hippie commune but this
circle
well i guess you'll find out in a future
episode
i'm really proud of the progress that's
been made in this episode alone to the
hippie hippie community shall we say
oh look there's red himself he's in he's
in his van what's he doing is he is he
is he on the toilet i think he might be
oh
oh sorry oh
sorry sorry
sorry ren
i'll um i'll leave you to it then i used
to think that these wandering traders
were really annoying
but i actually think that they're kind
of useful because these guys find you
wherever you are but you could just get
free leather every time they turn up and
some leads although the wandering
villagers themselves aren't that useful
but the llamas anyway i think that's
actually quite enough of the hippie area
because i actually want to go and
try out scars new minigame which is the
giant airplane that we didn't know what
it was last time
so i need to go and read what this is oh
and there's a giant target now
so i heard that this is a flying
minigame meaning that i should be able
to be quite good at it
welcome to the diamond drop please read
the instructions the objective is to
catch as many diamonds as possible while
free falling from the plane if you die
the diamonds must be returned to the
diamond chest of the tent
the diamonds you catch and land with are
your prize place your items in the
locker take five rockets pay here take
one parachute
well it seems this seems simple enough
oh i totally forgot that i have to pay
five diamonds for two jumps okey-dokey
well there we are five diamonds let's
give this a go whoa whoa whoa
pre-fight checklist one sleep in bed two
pay take one elytra take five rockets
fly up to the airplane okay well i've
gotta wait for night
that's gonna take too long i need to
play right now so we've gotta fly up to
the airplane and i need to
i need to save as many rockets as i can
oh really i'm only i'm only going to end
up with one rocket for this
all right skydivers welcome to diamond
drop press the button and wait for
flight stand on that trapdoor so i guess
i just press this i wait for the drop
go
i've got one diamond come on give me
that
i see
okay i made it back
so where does everything drop oh man
i totally lost like 90 levels
i have no idea where everything ends up
so i think i have to return these
okay so let's try this again that was
just a practice run i've never played
this game before so i wasn't quite sure
so i need to get up there as easily as
possible without using too many rockets
okay i managed to do it with two spare
this time if i actually make it come on
yeah we should make that okay i've got
two rockets this time
right this is this is drop two
do i fall fast or do i have to dive
there we go
got the diamond
does that count is that it i got oh my
goodness i got 11 diamonds capture as
many diamonds as possible before
activating your elytra parachute timing
of the release is crucial for success
it doesn't say anything about not using
the fireworks as you fall so it says
you got to do that and then you got to
pull your parachute out but i don't
think scar knows that you can totally
change your trajectory with the 5x i've
checked everywhere and there is nothing
about it it just says take five rockets
and it doesn't i guess you could just
use the rockets how you like guys i am
about to take every diamond scar has
from this minigame
let's do it 10 diamonds for four runs
so let's take our five rockets here
so i got my five rockets got my elytra
we're about to take scar
for every diamond he's put in this mini
game all right here we go again
go
diamond diamond
look
oh did i miss the block
[Music]
i missed the block that time
okay so i actually i made four diamonds
okay another five rockets here we go
again this is
two out of four here we go
one diamond two diamond
i only got three i still made a profit
on it
okay this is actually a little bit
harder than i thought however
we're still making some diamonds
so i got two more runs right drop three
here we go there i saw i saw the diamond
block right here
yes i got it yes i got it
snatched it on the air i don't know how
many diamonds i'm missing but as long as
i get the block it's totally worth it
all right
we put the rockets back
we grab another five rockets scar i hope
you've loaded this thing to the brim
with diamonds because
i'm about to be the champion
and i only need one rocket to do this
all right this is number four out of
four
uh there's no diamond there's no
diamonds left
there's no diamonds left
scar you owe me a run of this game
you owe me a run
even with an empty last run
we made
well how many diamonds did we make we've
spent 10 diamonds here
and we got 19 back
easiest nine diamonds i ever made i'm
gonna ask him to refill it and then i'm
just gonna play this game until it's
empty again and then i'm gonna ask him
to refill it honestly i think i've
broken the hermitcraft mini game system
easy easy money
so scar owes me one run but speaking of
mini games i've actually made a little
bit of progress on this manner here
which is actually one of my mini games
now this is basically the floor is lava
which is a fantastic game to play in
any situation
so i've added this graveyard outside
this is basically just to be decoration
because what's underneath is what's
important it's going to be a crypt oh
i'm still totally wearing so what i've
done is decorated just a couple of the
rooms i haven't actually linked up any
redstone yet but you can see these
dispensers these are going to release
the tokens so people jump around they
collect the tokens and then they've got
to get out obviously anything that's air
down here is going to be lava and it's
going to be pretty dangerous and you've
got to take a leap of faith sometimes to
get to the hidden uh
to the hidden dispensers and it's going
to be a lot of fun because if you want
the top prizes in this game you've
really got to explore it and try and get
to the more dangerous locations
and sometimes you've got to activate
some trap doors if you want to get to
say up here well
some some places like so and everyone
that's tried this so far has ended up
there which would mean death and it's
it's very easy to mess up and obviously
the more you explore the more chance you
have of falling in the lava however i
quickly realized that this is a project
that's going to take me multiple
episodes so i feel like i've made some
decent progress here and i need to make
some more dispensers and stuff but uh
it's going to take me a while to finish
this one i think unfortunately and then
i need to make
a little area over here with all the
tokens so it's going to be like an
arcade so so the prizes would be like
you know maybe a box full of diamonds
but you'd have to play this game
multiple times and be successful in
order to get the tokens for it i also
want to offer a quick apology for not
having any videos for over a week now i
haven't actually been at home at all
i've been away i think i said it in my
last episode but i know that a week is
quite a long time on the internet but
i'm back now and i'm working on new
videos
all day every day and hopefully we'll
see a lot more hermitcraft and some
other things as well so thank you very
much for all of your support but there's
actually quite a lot that's been added
while i've been away on my rest and
relaxation
specifically over there by the way what
i'm doing here is just adding a bit of
decoration to the hermit land sign i
thought it could use
something here just just to fill the
space a little bit more but that hermit
land sign has actually been replicated
right over here so we've got an
identical one that i assume
cub has made
right here and it enters the second half
of hermit land and guess what those
cheeky con corpse
they've made a food truck and they're
selling golden carrots two stacks for
one diamond and they're actually selling
their carrots why why are people buying
from concord and not my sahara eats over
there
that's
i was there first
we might have to undercut them in price
because
that's really whoa
whoa
the hermitcraft party bus is leaving the
station everyone is on board am i here
oh no there i am
i'm just sitting on the back i don't
know what's going on here but this is
awesome
guess what opening soon oh wow that's
cool we got a roller coaster
this is awesome hermit land is becoming
one of the best projects on hermitcraft
right now there's just so much
entertainment the games are fun the
builds are quite cool actually the
builds could look a little better
the builds could look a little better
but they are for they're for
entertainment purposes not to look good
although i must admit i've always had a
bit of a sweet spot for that mansion of
mine anyway i'm afraid i have run out of
time for today but we did get an awful
lot done actually we have made some
significant progress to the flores lava
game now this is obviously gonna take me
a long time we bled scar dry on this one
as soon as he restocks all of those
diamonds in there i'm gonna get so good
at that minigame that he's going to have
to close down
we have made significant progress to the
hippie commune over here by adding our
own custom terrain with a cliff and look
at ren
doing his thing
and we added our own little farm under
over here which goes underground and
we've got a little secret circle thing
going on over there we've been busy and
there's more to come so i will see you
in the next episode thank you very much
for watching and good bye